Baha Rababah

Winnipeg, Manitoba
Mobile: (+1)431-990-1908
email: Baharababah@yahoo.com

Web page: https://baharababah.github.io/website/

Enthusiastic and dedicated master computer science and engineering with two masters degrees and with experience in data engineering, machine learning, programming, and networking. Wide range of knowledge in computer science and engineering, involving build and test a high quality machine learning projects, as well as proven the ability to design and implement Internet of Things systems. For more details, open my CV.

Keywords: Machine Learning, Blockchain, Python, Node-Red, Java, Data Structure, Java Script, PHP, C++, Assembly, Internet of Things, Windows server, Linux, and CCNA,.

Education and Qualifications:

University of Manitoba, Canada.
 MSc Computer Science.

Sep 2018 – April 2021

University of Portsmouth, United Kingdom.
 Sep 2014 – Sep 2015
 MSc Computer Network Administration and Management.

• Al-Balqa Applied University, Jordan. Sep 2006 – July 2010 BSc Computer Engineering.

Programming Skills:

- Experience in Machine Learning programming Using Python (MSc Thesis and several Freelancer projects).
- Experience in Data Analysis: worked with a team for blockchain data analysis, my task was to cluster user behavior pattern (The project: https://github.com/cakcora/Chainoba).
- Build several machine learning and data analysis projects (check My portfolio in my web page).
- Web Programming: designed an online library website called Engineering Publication Library using PHP, CSS, MySQL and HTML.
- Experience in Data structure programming using java and C++ (Teaching data structure at university level).
- Experience in low level programming using Assembly (Teaching microprocessor at university level).

Operating Systems and Networking Skills:

- Knowledge of Microsoft Windows Server, client, and active directory.
- Knowledge of basic configuration and managing Linux networks.
- Knowledge of basic firewall configurations to meet the network security requirement and worked with SMTP, POP3, FTP, HTTPS, SSH and others protocols.
- Analyzing network packets using Wireshark and ColaSoft.
- Knowledge of network's Simulation to better understand its strengths and weaknesses.
- Experience in implementing network protocols, such as BGP, OSPF, and RIP (MSc Project).
- Experience in cloud computing: installing and configure OpenStack, working on IBM cloud to handle and process external data.

Hardware Skills:

- Experience in implementing Internet of Things applications Using *Raspberry Pi*, Arduino and sensors (MSc Thesis).
- Experience in flow streaming programming to connect hardware devices using Node-Red and Java Script (MSc Thesis).

Relevant Experience:

- **Full time Lecturer**, Faculty of Computer and Information System, Islamic University of Madinah, Saudi Arabia. Sep 2016 –Sep 2018.
- Lecturer of Information Technology, Arabian Education and Training Group, Amman, Jordan. Sep 2015 –Sep 2016
- Computer helpdesk and data entry operator provide support on a wide range of equipment and software, such as Windows, Office etc. Ministry of interior, Bahrain. 1 Jan 2012 1 Aug 2014
- Attending to CCNA course (50) hours, Amman, Jordan, 2009.

Awards:

- Faculty of Graduate Studies Program Completion Scholarship (2500\$), University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Canada, April 2021.
- Certificate of Honorable Achievement for substantial contribution to ABET accreditation of the academic programs of the Faculty of Computer and Information Systems, Islamic University in Madinah, Saudi Arabia, 2018.
- Best student certificate, MSc Computer Network Administration and Management, University of Portsmouth, UK, 2015.
- Best performance certificate, MSc Computer Network Administration and Management, University of Portsmouth, UK, 2015.